=The Embroidered Truth=
Meng Wan.
You've truly let me down.
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
Just now,
when Yu Ming presented the
"Spring River" to the Princess Consort,
were you mute?
You saw it too.
Lady Cheng'en didn't give me
a chance to speak.
Fine.
Then let me ask you this.
The manor is heavily guarded.
The gown and the box,
you were the only one watching them.
So, how come there are rats?
=Episode 16=
Forgive me, Your Highness.
I've always served Lord Cheng'en
at the military camp.
I'm not an inner court guard.
I've never seen Lady Cheng'en.
But coincidentally,
I have seen Lady Cheng'en's
personal maid, Xiaotao.
Since Xiaotao isn't here,
please forgive my presumption.
Allow me
to verify Lady Cheng'en's identity.
Mr. Xiao, I am fine.
Just give me the letter.
My Lady.
How is my father?
He is in good health.
He often speaks of you,
worried you might be wronged.
Tell him
that Wenyue treats me well.
He doesn't need to worry.
Yes.
Wenyue,
now that the delivery has arrived,
let Mr. Xiao have a rest.
I can't wait to see the new fabrics.
Meng Wan.
A rat chewed the silk.
The pheasant's head was severed.
You're trying to get me killed.
You've planned this carefully.
Too bad, you can't bring me down.
I've always stayed by your side.
You're wrong to suspect me.
Is that so?
Then help me one more time.
No matter who did this,
say it was you.
You're throwing me away.
Throw you away?
Or your family?
Fly high. Don't look back.
Our lives rest on your wings.
The situation is escalating.
The whole city is hunting us.
But hiding here forever
won't solve anything.
We've waited so long
to take down Wu Lian.
Hold on a little longer.
Here, have something to eat.
Your Highness,
I failed to guard the gown.
My master is innocent.
Let me bear this punishment.
Today, I received a gift
from Cheng'en Manor.
I should be happy.
But you two showed
great disrespect.
Your Highness,
I failed to guard it.
But the Flower Festival is near.
You need a gown to wear.
Let me redeem myself.
Redeem yourself?
If everyone could redeem themselves,
then my cousin,
the Princess Consort, could be
bullied by commoners.
Your Highness,
the Flower Festival nears.
In this city,
no one embroiders better than him.
Guards.
Take Meng Wan
to the manor's death row.
After the Flower Festival,
execute her.
Move.
Wenyue.
Ruoheng.
This is an official matter.
Why don't you
take me to see the brocade
you brought?
I met briefly with Mr. Xiao.
He said that meeting Miss Rulan,
he made no mistakes.
But the Princess Consort's nanny
seems suspicious.
Miss Rulan going to the manor
alone is already a crime.
And our previous actions
caused too much commotion.
The Princess Consort knows the Prince
returns soon.
To please him,
even if she knows the truth,
she has to accept Miss Rulan
as Lady Cheng'en.
That's like
putting her head on the blade.
She could die at any moment.
The fashionable fabrics from
the capital are so vibrant.
Wenyue, you grew up in
the capital.
The noble ladies and matrons,
when have they ever had
a fixed standard?
Fashion just chases novelty.
(Chases novelty...)
(If the Prince didn't chase novelty,)
(why would I have brought
you to Jinxiu City?)
(A Fine Gift from Cheng'en Manor)
Your Highness,
this fabric truly has
excellent weave.
(A Fine Gift from Cheng'en Manor)
Why is Ruoheng's personal seal on it?
Right.
Your Highness, according to protocol,
it should bear the seal
of Cheng'en Manor.
(Oh no.)
(Ruoheng used her personal seal.)
Perhaps Lady Cheng'en used her
personal seal for official matters,
not caring for such formalities.
Ruoheng, you were careless.
Your personal seal is for private use.
Why use it for official gifts?
Wenyue.
Wenyue,
I was careless.
Given our bond as cousins,
where is the impropriety?
As for you, merchant,
first, you curse my cousin
with a headless pheasant.
She was lenient enough not to pursue it.
Now, you attack me?
You're trying to drive a wedge
between us.
Ruoheng,
Master Wu may not have meant that.
Wenyue,
if he meant well,
why attack me again and again?
I am your cousin.
Of course I look out for you.
The Flower Festival is coming.
The Prince returns soon.
And he sows discord.
Master Wu,
it's obvious you want me out.
If I leave,
how does that benefit you?
Enough.
It's just a seal.
Master Wu, don't make
a big deal of nothing.
Ruoheng,
just prove it to him.
What's the harm?
Wenyue,
I'm just angry that a lowly merchant
dares to criticize me.
In that case,
you should produce you personal seal
to prove its authenticity.
I personally wrote the words
on this box's seal.
And my father had a craftsman
make this seal just for me.
Wenyue, surely you've heard of this.
Though I don't have the
seal on me now,
you can compare my handwriting
to the characters on the seal
and see if I'm telling the truth.
♪Night fades before the dawn♪
♪Old vows still guide my hand♪
♪The past no longer binds♪
♪My heart still shines through dust♪
♪Silent blooms, unchanged heart♪
♪Bare hands weave through the frost♪
♪Shadows linger, rain returns♪
♪Honor crowns my weary soul♪
♪For your faith that never broke♪
♪I shattered all the love I knew♪
♪No regrets, no debts unpaid♪
♪At dusk I walk away alone♪
♪If this tale becomes a storm♪
♪Old shadows fade from sight♪
♪One thought turns into ash♪
♪No future left to write♪
♪If I never fall♪
♪How could this waiting end♪
♪If I bear no scars♪
♪How could I challenge fate♪
♪I knew there was no way back♪
♪Yet I left this hope behind♪
♪For your faith that never broke♪
♪I shattered all the love I knew♪
♪No regrets, no debts unpaid♪
♪At dusk I walk away alone♪
♪If this tale becomes a storm♪
♪Old shadows fade from sight♪
♪One thought turns into ash♪
♪No future left to write♪
♪The lamp is out, you're gone♪
♪Heaven and earth fall silent♪
♪If we meet again someday♪
♪This longing sleeps beneath the snow♪